# Josh Woodcock // Front-End Software Engineer

832-247-8742 // josh@j0w0.com // github.com/j0w0 // j0w0.com // linkedin.com/in/jrwoodcock

**Front-End Software Engineer** experienced in building reliable, manageable, and scalable websites and web applications. I develop quality products by utilizing appropriate technologies and applying best practices for data organization and code optimization.

**Skills/Technologies:** React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SCSS, TypeScript, Vite, Next.js, Node, Express, Google Firebase, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Bootstrap, Tailwind, jQuery, PHP, Git, creating and consuming APIs, Wordpress CMS, WooCommerce. Code and project demos are available on my GitHub.

# **Experience**

## **Full-Stack Developer**

Hahn Agency | May 2022-Present | Austin, Texas

- Built a Learning Management System consisting of webinar video content, quizzes, and levels for achievement badges.
- Develop, implement, and maintain new features for client websites, apps, and content management systems.
- Tech stack includes React, JavaScript, HTML, SCSS/CSS, PHP, MySQL, Wordpress.

# **Front-End Software Engineer**

Music Audience Exchange (MAX) | January 2021-May 2022 | Austin, Texas

- Developed front end of brand and artist web apps for streaming concerts, including real-time chat and donations.
- Simplified development process for quicker turnaround by creating standardized templates for content and layout.
- Tech stack used includes React, Styled Components, Google Firebase, HTML, CSS, JavaScript.

### Front-End/UX Developer

Remedy Urgent Care | January 2019-July 2020 | Austin, Texas

- Streamlined urgent care web app that helped win two stages of funding for the start-up. By leveraging open-source web technologies, e-commerce, and custom form flows, the app was easily managed, scaled, and monitored.
- Developed admin utilities to help service coordinators better assist patients during the scheduling process.
- Tech stack used includes PHP, MySQL, Wordpress, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Twilio, WooCommerce.

#### **Web Developer**

Ford Audio-Video | January 2017-January 2019 | Austin, Texas

- Architected/developed custom Wordpress theme and plugins allowing for easier management and sharing of content.
- Developed and maintained full-stack web apps in PHP and MySQL for marketing events that included customer and exhibitor registration, check in and attendance, lead tracking, and online payments via Stripe.
- Tech stack used includes PHP, MySQL, Wordpress, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Twilio, Stripe.

### **Digital Media Marketing Coordinator**

Ford Audio-Video | July 2014-January 2017 | Austin, Texas

 Maintained earlier versions of the company's website, event landing pages, and staff Intranet. Designed and developed responsive email template for marketing promotions. Promoted to Engineering as Web Developer.

#### **Education**

### **Texas State University**